Wrege, Charles D. Papers 6012
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Sanford Thompson Records supplement those already at CU, and William C. Whitney data from the Library of Congress which holds a large amount of information on him. Whitney influenced Taylor through the Manufacturing Investment Co. Whitneys descendan (Box 10)
  - John D. Stelling Letter on Thompson Files, Thompson-Lichtner 5/30/78, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - John Stelling Letter of 9/13/78, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Letter to John Stelling on Thompson Papers July 4, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - John Stelling Letters (Thompson-Lichtner Co) - Stelling-Thompson, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - John Stelling, Thompson and Lichtner, 111 First Street, Cambridge, MA, Taylor 1983, 1926-1984 (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Thompson and Lichtner Co. and Data on Miles Nelson Clair, SM in Civil Engineering MIT 1923, 1974-1975 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - George Hanshaw in NYC Directory 1852-1855 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - On John Stelling - Letter from John Seeger, Dec. 10 1986, On Old Records at Thompson and Lichtner (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - Notes on Correspondence in Sanford Thompson's 1902 Letter Book (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - John Nartowicz (Rutgers Student Oct. 22, 1978) on visit to "Boxly" (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - John Stelling and the Taylor Biography Manuscript and Letter to Mrs. Ward Beckwith - 1978, 80, 83, 84, 1978-1984 (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - William C. Whitney Data 1899 (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - William C. Whitney Data (Letters from and to James Gonalon, Difalco, Eric Nolan 1982) - Whitney's Accountant, Library of Congress, 1905- 1982 (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - William C. Whitney and Naval Efficiency 1885, 1885-1889 (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - Data on William Whitney Papers and NY and Erie RR Papers in Library of Congress 1982 (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - Manufacturing Investment Company, 1893-1983 (Box 10, Folder 58)
    Copies and original documents, transparency
  - W.C. Whitney, D. Lamont, and Taylor, Donald Dickinson, 1897-1990 (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - W.D. Basley and the NY Providence and Boston RR, 1885-1984 (Box 10, Folder 60)
  - Great Northern Paper Co. (Acquired MIC in 1900), 1965 (Box 10, Folder 61)
  - Data on Daniel Lamont and William C. Whitney, Oliver Payne in Relation to W. Basley (on Lamont's Death July 24, 1905), 1905- 1981 (Box 10, Folder 62)
  - Data in Whitney Papers - in Library of Congress 1982 (Box 10, Folder 63)
  - William C. Whitney and Electric Cabs - Whitney 1898, 1897-1898 (Box 10, Folder 64)
  - Shadbolt, 1906 (Box 10, Folder 65)
  - Heinzer Paper on Whitney, Ryan, and Automobile Industry, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 66)
  - Dr. Orr Letters, Library of Congress, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 67)
  - Data on Whitney (On Street Railways - Metropolitan Traction Co.) (Box 10, Folder 68)
  - Note to Jean Cevasco 9/25/81 on Whitney and Basley, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 69)
  - Letter to Oliver Orr, Library of Congress - 11/20/81 on Whitney Papers and Rhode Records, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 70)
  - Annual Report on the Secretary of the Navy - 1887 (Dec. 6, 1887), 50th Congress, 2nd Session, Dec. 3, 1888 - March 2, 1889, p. XXIX (On 32 of 6" Guns with Midvale Steel Works) (Box 10, Folder 71)
  - William C. Whitney Will Search - June 23, 1981, Whitney-Taylor (Box 10, Folder 72)
  - Dunn and Bradstreet Reports on Houston West St. and Pavonia Ferry RR 12/5/91 (Related to W.C. Whitney) - Taylor-Whitney, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 73)
  - Article on Whitney, Ryan, and Widner and Metropolitan St., NY (NYC), McClure's Magazine - Nov. 1907, Whitney-Taylor Book (Box 10, Folder 74)
  - McClure's Magazine - Nov. 1907 on William C. Whitney and Metropolitan St., NY (relates to Taylor) - Taylor Book (Box 10, Folder 75)
  - W. C. Whitney and Metropolitan St. NY, 1899 (Box 10, Folder 76)
  - NY Times, Illustrated Magazine, Nov. 20, 1898 on William C. Whitney and Metropolitan Traction Co. - Use for Taylor (Box 10, Folder 77)
  - Barbara Paritte Data on Whitney 1893 (Box 10, Folder 78)
  - William C. Whitney Data, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 79)
  - Metropolitan Street NY Data (on News pages) 2/06/08, 1908 (Box 10, Folder 80)
  - Consolidated Traction Co. St, NY, Jl. May 1893, p. 345, col. 1, 1892-1901 (Box 10, Folder 81)
  - Incorporation Paper of Metropolitan Traction Co. NJ Feb. 20, 1892 (Whitney Not At Incorporation but Thomas T. Ryan is Listed) (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - F.W. Taylor Letter to W.C. Whitney - Library of Congress, Whitney Papers, 8/27/1891, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 83)
  - William C. Whitney Papers at Library on Congress Manuscript Division - 1982 (Box 10, Folder 84)
  - William C. Whitney Portrait - 1889 (Box 10, Folder 85)
    Copy of original photo
  - Research on William C. Whitney, Book Keeping, etc., 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 86)
  - William C. Whitney Papers at Library of Congress, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 87)
  - William C. Whitney and Taylor, Taylor Book, 1917-1990 (Box 10, Folder 88)
  - Search for Francis L. Stetson Papers (Associated with W.C. Whitney) - Taylor Book 1981 (Box 10, Folder 89)
  - Data from William C. Whitney Papers in Library of Congress 1982, Whitney-Taylor, 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 90)
  - Will of William Calhoun - Oct. 11 1889 - File Under Whitney Accounting (Box 10, Folder 91)
  - Survey of William C. Whitney Papers - 1982 (Box 10, Folder 92)
  - Library of Congress on Daniel S. Lamont Papers (MS-62-4600) and G. Cleveland Papers (MS-62-4985) on Whitney and Lamont and Basley and Taylor, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 93)
  - Whitney Material Mgt. Investment Co. 1981, 1891-1981 (Box 10, Folder 94)
  - Letters to Yale on Whitney, Payne Dimoch, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 95)
  - William C. Whitney and Taylor Naval Bookkeeping 1885, 1885-1982 (Box 10, Folder 96)
  - Report of New York and Northern Sept. 30, 1889 (Whitney and Basley) (Box 10, Folder 97)
  - Search for Whitney Papers and F.W. Taylor - 2-12-82, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 98)
  - Data on Electric Boat, and NY Electric Vehicle Transportation Co. (1899) - Whitney (Box 10, Folder 99)
  - Balance Sheet of Naval Stores by William Calhoun for W. Whitney 1888, 1888-1986 (Box 10, Folder 100)
  - William C. Whitney Papers in the Library of Congress 1990, 1896-1990 (Box 10, Folder 101)
  - William C. Whitney Papers - Library of Congress (on Taylor), 1891-1954 (Box 10, Folder 102)
  - Search for William Basley and F.W. Taylor in the William C. Whitney Papers in Library of Congress - 2-12-82, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 103)
  - Data on William C. Whitney, U.S. Navy and William Calhoun 1885-1889, 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 104)
  - International Sulphite Fibre and Paper Company (Annual Reports 1887, 1889, 1891, 1892, 1893), 1887-1893 (Box 10, Folder 105)
  - List of Owners of Manufacturing Investment Company Stock 8/22/91 (in Whitney Book 65 Library of Congress), 1991 (Box 10, Folder 106)
  - Data on Oliver Payne (Brother-in-Law of William Whitney) - Whitney, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 107)
  - Library of Congress (on Whitney Papers) - Whitney-Taylor, 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 108)
  - Data on Richard S. Hayes (Connect to William C. Whitney), 1882-1985 (Box 10, Folder 109)
  - Data on Richard Somers Hayes 1982 (Related to W.C. Whitney) (Box 10, Folder 110)
  - Richard S. Hayes and Taylor, 1905 (Box 10, Folder 111)
  - Richard S. Hayes Search 1982 (Associated with Taylor and Whitney in 1893), 1888-1982 (Box 10, Folder 112)
  - New York Transportation Co., New York Electrical Vehicle Transportation Co. (W.C. Whitney and Daniel Basley), 1899-1982 (Box 10, Folder 113)
  - Electric Vehicle Transportation Co., Electrical World vol XXXVII, No. 1 (Jan 5, 1901) - Controlled by William C. Whitney (Box 10, Folder 114)
  - Electric Vehicle Co. et al, in Electrical World and: Obsolete American Securities and Corporations, R.M. Smythe, NY 1904, and: Marvyn Scudders, Manual of Extinct and Obsolete Companies, NY 1926, 1898-1899 (Box 10, Folder 115)
  - Correspondence with William Kruger- Institute of Paper Chemistry 1981 on Watermarks (Taylor) - Taylor Book (Box 10, Folder 116)
  - Letter from Plank Corporation, Appleton, Wisconsin "Dandy" Rolls and Watermarks, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 117)
  - Studies in Watermarks (Box 10, Folder 118)
    Index Cards
  - Letter on Crane Watermarks from Winthrop Crane 10/21/81 - Watermarks, 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 119)
  - Hawthorne Output - Study of Watermarks, 1931 (Box 10, Folder 120)
  - Watermarks on Carl Barth Papers at Harvard 1982, 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 121)
  - Data on Watermarks, 1899-1917 (Box 10, Folder 122)
  - Watermarks on Various Taylor Documents, 1893 (Box 10, Folder 123)
  - Watermarks and Typing Peculiarities in Ind. Mgt. and Principles of Scientific Mgt. 1977, and Letter to Richard Wolf 1981 on Gravel and Watermarks (Box 10, Folder 124)
  - Horace K. Hathaway Accounting Report on Newton Mailine Tools Works (Watermarks) (Box 10, Folder 125)
  - Watermarks ("Fairfield First Quality") on Taylor Bookkeeping Pages Dated June 2, 1896 - Taylor, Watermarks (Box 10, Folder 126)
  - Letter to T. Gravell on Watermarks - 1981 (Box 10, Folder 127)
  - The Plank Corporation, Appleton, Wisconsin (on Papers and Watermarks 1981) - Taylor (Box 10, Folder 128)
  - Eaton, Crane, and Pike Papers and Watermarks (By Kepple Hall 1915) (Box 10, Folder 129)
  - Gravell Correspondence, Watermarks Research 1981 (Box 10, Folder 130)
  - Crane Museum on Watermarks 10/10/1981 (Box 10, Folder 131)
  - Copies of Outline on How to Close Books Under Taylor System, Accounting - Taylor, 1896-1981 (Box 10, Folder 132)
  - Taylor's Discussion of Gantt Paper, Dec. 5, 1901, Mentioning Pig-Iron Handling - Taylor 1901 (Box 10, Folder 133)
  - Watermarks Data 1981 (Box 10, Folder 134)
  - Watermarks, Acct. Papers at Barth Papers at Baker Library, Harvard Univ., 1981 (Box 10, Folder 135)
  - 1981 Correspondence with Crane Paper Co on Watermarks (Box 10, Folder 136)
- Steel Motor Co. and Manufacturing Investments Co. (lots) owned by William C. Whitney (Taylor had stock in it too). It is the first place that Taylor did real work outside of Midvale. Maps, reports by Edward Rhodey? from Consolidated Papers in Wiscon (Box 11)
  - Data on F.W. Taylor Laboratory Univ. PA 1950, 1950-1953 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Mrs. Taylor to Thompsons, Dec. 26, 1935 on Smaller Taylor Biography (copy) (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Mrs. Taylor's Letters, 1896-1948 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Frederick Taylor and Lawn Tennis - from Fifty Years of Lawn Tennis in the US 1931, 1931-1989 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Dec. 17, 1874, p. 4, Iron Age on Mechanical Laboratory at Stevens Institute of Technology on Donation of Laboratory by a "Friend" (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - M.L. Cooke Agreement with Harpers Feb. 1911 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Scientific Mgt., U.S. Unions 1966, 1914-1966 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - News Items on Johnson Co. 1896, 1897, 1901, 1902 (Steel Motor Co.), 1896-1902 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Thomas F. Bayard Papers - Library of Congress (Guide), Bayard Related to Steel Motor Co., Johnstown, PA, 1933-1963 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - FWT to Capt. C.F. Goodrich on Johnson Co., Johnstown, PA 6/3/96, 1896 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Data on Johnson Company 1890, Johnstown, PA (use for FW Taylor) (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Steel Motor Co., (Johnson Co) Johnstown, PA (Taylor was connected 1896), Taylor built house here in 1896, 1896-1991 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Richard Burkart, Johnstown Flood Museum on Taylor and Johnson Co., 1984 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - James Mapes Dodge and the Link-Belt Co., 1980 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    Folder with original documents
  - Link-Belt - Tabor (at 6225 Tacony St., Phila. 1953) F.R. Wallace Pres., Robert M. Maull, Secretary (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - W.H. McElwain Shoe Co., 1915, Letter to Kempton Taylor on Ideas to Work with Taylor Prior to His Death 8/13/15, 1915-1917 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Ames Shovel Co., Archives, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Ames Mgt. Co. vs. Taylor Barbara Klimek - Taylor Book 1985 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - T. Coonahan Letter to Taylor, Feb. 3, 1896 on Data on Unloading Coal at Midvale (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Scientific Shoveling Booklet (Copy) From Stone Hill College (Mrs. Louise Kenneally) 5/15/91, 1911-1991 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Stone Hill College (North Easton, MA 02357), Collection of Ames Shovels - and Data on Ames and Rowland Shovel Co. - 1991 (Letter from Louise M. Kenneally, 5/7/91) - Taylor, Shovels, 1901-1991 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    Copy and original documents
  - Wyoming Shovel Works - 1964 (Letter from H.D. Potter) (Box 11, Folder 22)
    Original envelope and letter
  - Forms for Inquiry on Wyoming Shovel Works - 1963 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Data on Wyoming Shovel Works, From: Wilkes-Barre Library, Mary Daly, Valley Crest, Wyoming, pa - 1/23/64, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - The Engineering and Mining Journal, Vol. 95, No. 16, p.20 of Selling Section, Wyoming Shovel Works Advertisement - For Taylor Book (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Wyoming Shovel Works Data 1963 - Taylor Book, 1963-1964 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Frederick W. Taylor and "Scientific Shoveling" in: Booklet Published by Wyoming Shovel Works, Wyoming, PA, (23 pp., n.d., NY Public Library # VDC PV 69, No. 12), 1911 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Data on Wyoming Shovel Works, Scranton PA (Advertisement on Taylor and Shoveling) - Taylor, Shoveling (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Taylor-Thompson, Coonahan 1896 on Shoveling (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Incorporation Papers Mgt. Investment Co. 1889, Acct. (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Data on New Ordinance Yard in Washington, NY Times, Oct. 1, 1886 (related to Taylor going to Washington, D.C.) (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Stockholders of International Sulphite Fibre and Paper Co., 1887-1893 (in 1893 Taylor held 5 shares) (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Balance Sheet Mgt. Investment Co., with "Investments: International Sulphite Paper Co.", 1890 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Annual Reports of the International Sulphite Fibre and Paper Co., 1888-1898 (Taylor had stock in it in 1898) and Alexander Mitscherlich Patent Data 41886 (patent 337,694) - Taylor 1898 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - International Sulphite Fibre and Paper Co and Taylor 1/24/85, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Annual Reports on International Sulphite Fibre and Paper Company 1889-1898 (Holders of Mitscherlich Pulp Paper Patents), 1985 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Mgt. Investment Co. Data, 1981-1983 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Letter to Ron Greenwood on Everett W. Rohde of Consolidated Papers - on Mgt. Investment Co., June 2, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - 1981- Letter and Material from Everett W. Rohde, Consolidated Papers, Appleton, Wisc. 5/28/81, 1892-1981 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - F.W. Taylor - Observations on Rate of Unloading Coal, Appleton, Wisc. 1892 - Copy of Original, For Taylor Book (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Everett Rohde Letters 1981 on Mgt. Investment Co. Records, 1893-1981 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Data on Appleton Newspapers in 1890's "The Crescent", 1899 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Information on Richmond Mill and William Fannon in Appleton, Wisc. 1981 - For Taylor Book (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - Letter from Everett Rohde of Consolidated Papers - Appleton, Wisc. 5/28/81 on Mgt. Investment Co., 1981 (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - Letter from Taylor to A.L. Smith (Appleton, Wisc.) 12-2-93 on "Flash Boards" Copy from Rohde (Mgt. Investment Co.), 1893 (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - Data on Interlake Pulp and Paper Co. (Formerly Mgt. Investment Co.) - Taylor from Rohde, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - Copies of Taylor Documents from Appleton, Wisconsin from Mr. Rohde - Taylor, 1892-1893 (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - Consolidated Papers Inc. 1981 (Successor to Mgt. Investment Co.) - Taylor, 1981-1983 (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence with Outagamie County Historical Society on Appleton Mill of Mgt. Inv. Company 1981 - on Taylor Letter with Beck Helland (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - Maine State Museum (on Mgt. Invest. Co.) Ron Kley - Taylor Book, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 50)
  - Manufacturing Investment Co. and International Sulphite Fibre and Pulp Co. 1983 - Taylor Book, 1981-1983 (Box 11, Folder 51)
  - To Arthur Lehto - Madison Paper Industries - on Old Mgt. Investment Records - 8/15/82, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 52)
  - Letters from Zip Kellogg of Univ. of Maine 11/16/81 on Mgt. Investment Co. Photos - Taylor 1981, 1891-1981 (Box 11, Folder 53)
  - Copies of Photos of Mgt. Investment Co. Madison, Maine 1889-1890, 1889-1982 (Box 11, Folder 54)
    Copies and originals of photos
  - Maine State Archives (on Mgt. Investment Co.) 9/22/81 - Taylor, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 55)
  - F.W. Taylor at Appleton, Wisc. 1981, 1892-1981 (Box 11, Folder 56)
  - Letter from John E. McLeod - Oakland, Maine 2/5/82 - On Mgt. Investment Co. (McLeod wrote a history), 1974-1982 (Box 11, Folder 57)
  - "The Manufacturing Investment Company" Chapter VI - For Taylor Book, 1974-1982 (Box 11, Folder 58)
  - Great Northern Nekoosa Corp. (Great Northern Paper Co.), 1891-1982 (Box 11, Folder 59)
  - Stockholders of Mgt. Investment Co. 1891 (Box 11, Folder 60)
    Transparency
  - Stockholders of Mgt. Investment Co. 1891 (Box 11, Folder 61)
  - Madison Historical Society (on Taylor, MIC, Basley) Mgt. Investment Co. - 1981 Taylor (Box 11, Folder 62)
  - F.W. Taylor to George Hammond on Leaving Mgt. Investment Co. May 18,1893 (copy) (Box 11, Folder 63)
  - George F. Steele Data (Friend of F.W. Taylor) - Taylor, Steele, Whitney, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 64)
  - F.W. Taylor Letters, MIC Letters, 12/2/1892, 2/11/1893, 1892-1893 (Box 11, Folder 65)
  - MIC Report 1892 (F.W. Taylor on "Unloading Coal") Manufacturing Investment Co. Report by Taylor, March 15, 1892 - Taylor (Box 11, Folder 66)
  - Map of Madison, Maine and MIC Mill, Mgt. Investment Co. - Taylor Book, 1907 (Box 11, Folder 67)
  - Xerox of Sanford Thompson's Notes from Mgt. Investment Co., Madison, Maine, 1890-1891 (Box 11, Folder 68)
  - F.W. Taylor Letter After Leaving MIC, 1892-1981 (Box 11, Folder 69)
  - F.W. Taylor's Activities After Leaving MIC - CDW 11/15/81 (1 page of 2-CDW 7/5/96), 1981 (Box 11, Folder 70)
  - Where F.W. Taylor was on Various Dates (to Verify Taylor's Statement of 10/16/1895 That He Was In "The West" in 1896) (Box 11, Folder 71)
  - Study of What F.W. Taylor Did After Leaving Mgt. Investment Co. in 1893 (Covers 1893-1896) CDW 1981 (use for Taylor Book) (Box 11, Folder 72)
  - U.S. District Court for the District of Maine, Equity Case 487, Archives Branch, Federal Archives and Record Center Waltham, Maine, Record Group 21 - Simonds vs. Hathorne 1899 Court of Appeals (Box 11, Folder 73)
  - Simonds Rolling Machine Co. Data - 1897, 1897-1898 (Box 11, Folder 74)
  - Simonds Rolling Machine Co. Data, 1985 - Plus Greenwood Letter, 1874-1985 (Box 11, Folder 75)
  - F. Taylor Agreement with Simonds Rolling Machine Co. on Selling Stock, Oct. 21, 1889 - Simonds (Box 11, Folder 76)
    Transparency of original document
  - Article on Simonds Rolling Machine Co., Fitchburg Daily Sentinel (No date, but probably 1893) (Box 11, Folder 77)
  - Simonds Rolling Machine Co. Data, 1985 Taylor, 1907-1985 (Box 11, Folder 78)
  - Fitchburg, Mass., City Directory 1894, on Simonds Rolling Machine Co., use 1888 on Simonds Projectiles, 1888-1894 (Box 11, Folder 79)
  - Information on Rolling Machine Companies and Steel Ball Mgt. Co.'s - C.D. Wrege 1985 (Box 11, Folder 80)
  - Letter from Fitchburg Historical Society 11/2/1983 on Simonds Rolling Machine Co. (to Laura McNamara), 1888-1983 (Box 11, Folder 81)
  - Fitchburg, Mass. Map - 1878 (Box 11, Folder 82)
  - Simonds Rolling Machine Data in Copley's Biography Vol. I, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 83)
  - Simonds Rolling Machine Co. Data 1896 - Simonds, 1896-1985 (Box 11, Folder 84)
  - Stockholders of Simonds Rolling Machine Co. 1890 - Simonds, Taylor (Box 11, Folder 85)
  - News Item on the Death of George Simonds (Osage City News, Kansas) Nov. 6, 1894 - Simonds (Box 11, Folder 86)
  - George Simmonds Portrait 1887 (Box 11, Folder 87)
  - Annual Report Simonds Rolling Machine Co., 1890 (Box 11, Folder 88)
  - Taylor Letters on Sale of Stock for Simonds Rolling Machine Co. 1889 (Box 11, Folder 89)
    Transparencies of original documents
  - Simonds Annual Report - Article of Inc. - Simonds, 1890 (Box 11, Folder 90)
  - Data on Simonds Rolling Machine Co. and McElwain from Douglas Noy 8/18/81, His Home Address: 621 Buchanan Boulevard, Red Bank, NJ 07701, 1893-1981 (Box 11, Folder 91)
  - Simonds Rolling Machine Co. Photos (Box 11, Folder 92)
  - Simonds Rolling Machine Advertisement, a Letter from Fitchburg Historical Society - 11/21, 1888-1983 (Box 11, Folder 93)
  - Data on Simonds Rolling Machine Co. 1985 - Taylor, 1890-1985 (Box 11, Folder 94)
  - Laura McNamara and 1984 Simonds Rolling Machine Co., 1897-1985 (Box 11, Folder 95)
  - "The Simonds Rolling Machine Co." in the 1892 Fitchburg Daily Sentinel - Souvenir Edition p.9 (Mass.) (Box 11, Folder 96)
    Transparency of original
  - Simonds Rolling Machine Co., Advertisement for Projectiles 1888 (Box 11, Folder 97)
  - Driggs-Seabury Gun Co., Derby, Connecticut 1900, 1889-1990 (Box 11, Folder 98)
  - Driggs-Seabury Gun and Ammunition Company, 1897 (Box 11, Folder 99)
- Simonds Patent Suit Continued. Data on Simonds, who played a big part in Taylors thinking.. (Box 12)
  - Taylor Testimony in "Simonds vs. Hathorn," October 11, 12, 15, 16, 18, 1897 (3 pages) - Taylor Book, 1916-1984 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Taylor and Industrial Espionage (1986) - Simonds, Wrege Paper on Simonds, 1895-1986 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Portion of a Letter to Ron Greenwood 1-19-85 (page 3-4) on Simonds Court Case (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - James Owens - Simonds Rolling Machine Co. Suit 1984 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Copies of Taylor Letters on Simonds Rolling Machine Testing 1896, 1896-1899 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Chauncey Smith-Patent Attorney, The RR and Engineering Journal, 1891 (August, p. 380) Taylor and Simonds (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Research into Simonds Rolling Machine Co., Fitchburg, MA, 1875-1895 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Simonds Letters, 1893-1897 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Simonds Rolling Machine Co., 1873-1921 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Purington, 1896 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Barbara Egan - Court Records on Simonds and Letter to Federal Records Center Waltham, Mass., 1984-1985 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - SH Shadbolt, Taylor 11/5/95 from Cleveland, Ohio (On Advertisement He Put In Paper), 1895 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Taylor to George Hathorne 3/7/98, 1898 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Search for S.H. Shadbolt 1984 (F.W. Taylor's "Spy") Simonds Rolling Machine Co., 1896-1897, 1890-1984 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Transparencies of Shadbolt Letter to F.W. Taylor 1895 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Shadbolt Letters to F.W. Taylor 2-28-97, 1895-1897 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - American Ball Association, 1895 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Simonds Transparencies 1983 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence with P. Peterson on Simonds Rolling Machine Co. and Taylor 1984 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Newcomb Carlton Letters on Rolling Machine Espionage 1895-96, 1890-1896 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Shadbolt Letters, 1895-1897 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Taylor Deposition in Simonds Case Oct. 11, 1897 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Hathorn Letters, Simonds Rolling Machine Co., 1897 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Simonds Rolling Machine Co. and Taylor: 1892 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Simonds Rolling Machine Co. and Taylor: 1895, 1895-1898 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Simonds Rolling Machine Co. and Taylor: 1896 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Simonds Rolling Machine Co. and F.W. Taylor 1888-1892, 1888-1893 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Simonds Data, Important 12/24/84, 1897-1899 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Notes on Taylor and Accounting2/24/1981, Simonds Rolling Machine Co. and Basley, 1893-1981 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - F.W. Taylor, Report to Directors Simonds Rolling Machine Co. 9/1/1896 - Taylor (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Simonds Rolling Machine Co. Letters, 1890-1896 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Nov. 22, 1895 - Letter from Newcomb Carlton to Taylor, 1895-1896 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Shadbolt Data, 1897 (Box 12, Folder 33)